Think on your sins.
Skyfall is a action, adventure, thriller film directed by Sam Mendes.
When Bond's latest assignment goes gravely wrong, agents around the
world are exposed and MI6 headquarters is attacked.
While M faces challenges to her authority and position from Gareth Mallory, the new Chairman of the Intelligence and
Security Committee, it's up to Bond, aided only by field agent Eve, to locate the mastermind behind the attack.
James Bond, played by Daniel Craig.
M, played by Judi Dench.
Silva, played by Javier Bardem.
Gareth Mallory, played by Ralph Fiennes.
Eve, played by Naomie Harris.
Séverine, played by Bérénice Marlohe.
Skyfall is a 2012 spy film and the twenty-third in the
James Bond series produced by Eon Productions.
The film is the third to star Daniel Craig as fictional MI6 agent James Bond and features
Javier Bardem as Raoul Silva, the villain, with Judi Dench returning as M.
The film was directed by Sam Mendes and written by Neal
Purvis, Robert Wade, and John Logan.
In the film, Bond investigates a series of targeted data leaks
and co-ordinated attacks on MI6 led by Silva.
It sees the return of two recurring characters, Miss Moneypenny (played by Naomie
Harris) and Q (played by Ben Whishaw), after an absence of two films.
Ralph Fiennes, Bérénice Marlohe, and Albert
Finney are among the supporting cast.
Mendes was approached to direct after the release of Quantum of Solace in 2008.
Development of the film was suspended throughout 2010 after Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer (MGM) filed for
Chapter 11 bankruptcy, which caused screenwriter Peter Morgan to leave the project.
Production resumed in December 2010 after Purvis, Wade, and Logan were hired
and a November 2012 release date was announced in January 2011.
Principal photography began that November after the film's title was revealed and lasted until
March 2012, with filming locations including London, Shanghai, Istanbul, and Scotland.
Skyfall premiered at the Royal Albert Hall on 23 October 2012, and was released theatrically in conventional and IMAX formats in the United
Kingdom three days later and in the United States on 9 November, to coincide with the 50th anniversary of the first James Bond film Dr.
Skyfall received positive reviews, with praise for Mendes's direction, cast
performances, action sequences, cinematography, and musical score.
The film was nominated for five awards at the 85th Academy Awards,
winning two, and received numerous other accolades.
Skyfall grossed over $1.1 billion worldwide becoming the fourteenth film to pass the billion dollar mark, the seventh-highest-grossing film of all
time at the time of its release, the highest-grossing James Bond film of all time, and the second-highest-grossing film of 2012.
The next film in the series, Spectre, was released in 2015.
The film explores themes of spy, secret agent,
sociopath, police impersonator, mi6.
The tone is intense.